Guide to the Vassar College Facilities Operations Records, 1800s-2021 (bulk 1908-1999)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Vassar College Facilities Operations Records
1800s-2021
1908-1999
Vassar College. Facilities Operations
circa 277 cubic feet (87 boxes, 368 roll boxes); map case folders
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Materials related to the actives of Vassar College Facilities Operations, including basic service, construction, renovation, and maintenance projects concerning the college’s buildings and property.
Administrative History
When Vassar College opened in 1861, Cyrus Swan was appointed as the first Superintendent, "charged with the general oversight, care and management of the grounds, buildings, furniture, apparatus, livestock and any other material property of the College." The superintendent supervised 80 employees devoted to the upkeep of the College's physical property. In 1905, a Trustee Committee on Landscape Gardening, later renamed the Committee on Buildings and Grounds, was established to oversee the activities of the superintendent and his staff. In 1916, the superintendent became a member of the college's Business Administration rather than an officer of the Board of Trustees, and by 1922 the position had been renamed General Manager.
In 1968, the position of General Manager was eliminated, and the Director of Plant Operations Division began reporting to the Vice President for Administration. Plant Operations was renamed Facilities Operations in 1984, at which time its offices were consolidated into the Service Building and its chief officer was the Director of Facilities Operations. In 1993, Facilities Operations was renamed Buildings and Grounds, and by 2016, the name had changed back to Facilities Operations.
Facilities Operations at Vassar College is responsible for the maintenance and improvement of the campus architecture and landscape. Building Trades, Grounds Services, Mechanical Services, Custodial Services, and the Work Control Center are administered by Facilities Operations. Other programs, such as Facilities Systems and Services, Project Management, Energy Management and the Service Response Center also fall under the jurisdiction of Vassar’s Facilities Operations. In addition to basic services, the department also provides materials and labor for special events, renovation projects and major construction or demolition services that require the assistance of outside contractors and service providers.
Source: An Administrative History of Vassar College, 1861-2003. Poughkeepsie, N.Y.: Vassar College, 2004.
Scope and Content Note
The collection contains materials related to the actives of Vassar College Facilities Operations (formerly the Buildings and Grounds Department), including basic service, construction, renovation, and maintenance projects concerning the college’s buildings and property. Records include reports, specifications, correspondence, blueprints, plans, photographs, financial information, and various other materials.
Arrangement
The collection is organized into two series: Series I. Administrative Files, 1879-2021; and Series II. Plans, 1800s-2021.
Access
This collection is open for research according to the regulations of the Vassar College Archives and Special Collections Library without any additional restrictions.
Related Materials
Jeh V. Johnson Papers, Vassar College Archives and Special Collections Library
Richard Keane Papers, Vassar College Archives and Special Collections Library
Vassar College Archives Files, Vassar College Archives and Special Collections Library
Vassar College Photograph Files, Vassar College Archives and Special Collections Library
Vassar College Subject Files, Vassar College Archives and Special Collections Library
Subject Headings
Organizations:
Vassar College--Athletics; Vassar College--Buildings; Vassar College. Art Gallery; Vassar College. Frances Lehman Loeb Art Center; Vassar College. Library; Vassar College. Observatory; Wimpfheimer Nursery School (Poughkeepsie, N.Y.)
Subjects:
Architecture--New York (State)--Poughkeepsie; Music-halls--New York (State)--Poughkeepsie
Document Types:
Architectural documents; Architectural drawings (visual works); Blueprints (reprographic copies); Building plans; Correspondence; Financial records; Floor plans (orthographic projections); Maps; Negatives (photographs); Plans (orthographic projections); Property records; Site plans
VCL Categories:
Administrative Offices and Functions
Encoding Information
Encoded by Matthew Thorenz, 2012.
Updated by Emma Gronbeck, March 2025.
Acquisition Information
Transferred in multiple accessions from multiple departments, particularly Vassar College Facilities Operations, 2003-2024. (A2003-016, A2003-021, A2004-015, A2006-016, A2007-047, A2009-014, A2010-020, A2010-024, A2010-025, A2011-003, A2013-043, A2014-033, A2016-029, A2024-020, A2025-033)
Series List
- Series I. Administrative Records, 1879-2021
- Series II. Plans, 1800s - 2021
  Scope and Contents
  Alumnae House, 1919-2004
  Athletics Facilities, 1974-2003
  Athletics Facilities - Walker Field House, 1981
  Baldwin Hall (Infirmary), 1938-1961
  The Bayit (Jewish Student Center), 1999
  Minnie Cumnock Blodgett Hall of Euthenics, 1916-1966
  Central Heating Plant (Boiler House, Coal Bins), 1916-2010
  Chapel, 1930-1966
  Chicago Hall, 1988
  College Center, undated
  Computer Center (Service Building), 1966-circa 1988
  Russell and Janet Doubleday Studio Arts Building, 1992
  Ely Hall (Alumnae Gymnasium), 1902-2010
  Facilities Operations Center (Buildings and Grounds Service Center), 1991
  Faculty Housing - General, [1891?]-1989
  Faculty Housing - Kendrick House, 1926
  Faculty Housing - Pratt House, 2021, undated
  Faculty Housing - Williams House, 1919-1941
  Farm and Ecological Preserve, 1905-1924, undated
  Gordon Commons (All College Dining Center (ACDC), Students' Building), 1912-1972
  Greenhouses, 1967
  Grounds, 1800s - 1992
  Jeh V. Johnson ALANA Center (Intercultural Center), 1992
  Kautz Admission House (Maids Club House, Good Fellowship House), 1912, undated
  Kenyon Hall, 1930-1997
  Library - Thompson, 1904-1998
  Library - Lockwood Addition, circa 1970-1974
  Library - Van Ingen Addition, 1930-1963
  Frances Lehman Loeb Art Center, 1990-1992
  Main Building, 1891-1989
  Metcalf House, 1915, 1970
  Seeley G. Mudd Chemistry Building, 1981-1989
  New England Building, 1900-1990
  New Hackensack Building, undated
  Observatory - Class of 1951, undated
  Observatory - Maria Mitchell, [1895]
  Old Laundry Building (Computer Center), 1964-1986
  Olmsted Hall of Biological Sciences, 1969-1973
  Poughkeepsie Day School, 1963
  Hallie Flanagan Davis Powerhouse Theater (Power Plant), 1965-1972
  President's House, [1895]
  Rockefeller Hall, 1896-1989
  Sanders Classroom (Sanders Chemistry), 1907-1989
  Sanders Physics, [1915]-1930
  Shiva Theater (Coal Bin Theater), undated
  Skinner Hall of Music, 1930-1991
  Student Housing - General, 1906-1971
  Student Housing - Cushing House, circa 1911-1970
  Student Housing - Davison House, 1966-1987
  Student Housing - Dexter M. Ferry Jr. Cooperative House (Ferry House), 1949-1950
  Student Housing - Jewett House (North Hall), 1966-1973
  Student Housing - Josselyn Hall, 1966/1972
  Student Housing - Lathrop House, circa 1900-1989
  Student Housing - Emma Hartman Noyes House, 1954-1974
  Student Housing - Raymond Hall, 1910-1989
  Student Housing - South Commons, undated
  Student Housing - Strong House, 1927-1990
  Student Housing - Terrace Apartments, 1972
  Student Housing - Town Houses, undated
  Swift Hall (Infirmary), 1899-1968
  Taylor Hall, 1911 - circa 1980s
  Utilities - Electric, 1930-1989
  Utilities - Heating and Cooling, 1927-1989
  Utilities - Miscellaneous, 1909-1971
  Vogelstein Center for Drama and Film (Avery Hall, Calisthenium and Riding Academy), 1874-1971
  Wimpfheimer Nursery School, 1926 - circa 1927
  Miscellaneous Building Plans, 1909-2004
  Unidentified and Unprocessed Plans, 1924-1975, undated
  Arrangement
  Materials in this collection are organized into subseries alphabetically by building or facility, with miscellaneous and unidentified plans filed at the end of the series. Materials within each subseries are arranged chronologically.
Container List
- Series I. Administrative Files, 1879-2011
  - Buildings - Acoustic Study, 1980 (Box 1)
  - [Student Housing] Dormitory Miscellaneous, 1984-1987 (Box 1)
  - [Student Housing] Dormitory Loan Change Order Bids, Etc., 1981-1986; (5 folders) (Box 1)
  - [Student Housing] Dormitories - Electric Meters, 1985 (Box 1)
  - [Student Housing] Dormitories - Smoke Detectors, 1984-1986 (Box 1)
  - [Student Housing] Dormitories - Temporary Housing, 1984 (Box 1)
  - [Student Housing] Dormitory Computers, 1983-1984 (Box 1)
  - Emergency Student Housing, 1983 (Box 1)
  - Energy Conservation Measure (ECM) Report Forms, 1983 (Box 1)
  - Energy Conservation Measure (ECM) I, III, V, Annual Reports, 1983-1986 (Box 1)
  - [Davison House] Davison House ECM - Cycle III, 1981 (Box 1)
  - Lathrop House ECM - Cycle III, 1981 (Box 1)
  - [Avery Hall] Avery Energy Conservation Measure (ECM), 1980 (Box 1)
  - [Main Building] Main Building ECM - Cycle II, 1980 (Box 1)
  - [Sanders Physics] Sanders Physics ECM, 1980 (Box 1)
  - [Sanders Classroom] Sanders Chemistry ECM, 1982 (Box 1)
  - [Raymond House] Raymond ECM, 1983 (Box 1)
  - [Metcalf House] Metcalf ECM, 1980 (Box 1)
  - [Swift Hall] Swift ECM, 1981 (Box 1)
  - [College Center - The Retreat] Retreat General File, 1988 (Box 1)
  - [Main Building] Cycle VI Bids, 1985 (Box 1)
  - [Main Building] Main Building Cycle VI - Reports, 1985-1987 (Box 1)
  - Notice of Grant Awards - V- VI-VIII, 1984-1986 (Box 1)
  - Energy Conservation Measure (ECM) Cycle VII, 1984-1985 (Box 1)
  - [College Center - The Retreat] Nova Mechanical - Pittsfield Pipers - Altieri, 1988 (Box 1)
  - [College Center - The Retreat] [Retreat - Equipment], 1988 (Box 1)
  - [College Center - The Retreat] Project Manuals, 1988 Mar-May; (2 folders) (Box 1)
  - [College Center - The Retreat] Retreat, 1988-1989; (3 folders) (Box 2)
  - [College Center - The Retreat] Centerbrook, 1988 (Box 2)
  - [College Center - The Retreat] Horton Lewis - Crabtree, 1988 (Box 2)
  - [College Center - The Retreat] Renovation, 1988-1989 (Box 2)
  - Pieces Selected for Vassar Views, 1934, 2002 (Box 2)
  - [General Manager] Reports of the General Manager to the President and Board of Trustees, Vassar College (V.C.), 1956-1967; (36 folders) (Box 2)
  - [General Manager] Reports of the General Manager to the President and Executive Committee, 1960-1966; (7 folders) (Box 2)
  - [General Manager] Memorandum from the General Manager to the Committee on Business Administration re the Vassar College Pension Plan and the Farm, 1956 Sep 28 (Box 2)
  - [General Manager] Memorandum from the General Manager to the Executive Committee re the Vassar College Pension Plan (Non - Academic Employees), 1956 Sep 11 (Box 2)
  - [General Manager] Minutes of Meeting of Committee on Business Administration on 21 Mar 1956 and Report of General Manager re College Pension Plan and Food Service, 1956 Apr 3 (Box 2)
  - [General Manager] Reports of the General Manager to the President and the Board of Trustees, Vassar College, 1945-1955; (29 folders) (Box 3)
  - [General Manager] Report of the General Manager to the Executive Committee re Sewer District, 1955 Apr 26 (Box 3)
  - [General Manager] Report of the General Manager to the Committee on Business Administration re Laundry and Farm, 1955 Apr 12 (Box 3)
  - Proposed Building Maintenance and Construction Program 1954/55, 1954 May 10 (Box 3)
  - Proposed Building Maintenance and Construction Program - 1953/54, 1953 Apr 22 (Box 3)
  - [Davison House] Davison House Fire Loss - Payment to Contractor, 1959 Mar 16 (Box 3)
  - [Davison House] Fire Loss - March 16 1959 - Davison House, Photographs, 1959 Apr 1 (Box 3)
  - [Davison House] Davison House Fire Loss March 16 1959 - Contracts (Box 3)
  - [Davison House] Davison House - Fire Loss, 1959 Mar 16 (Box 3)
  - [Davison House] Davison House- Fire Damage, Photographs, 1959 Jun 7 (Box 3)
  - Seventy-Fifth Anniversary, 1940 (Box 3)
  - Seventy-Fifth Anniversary - Housing, 1939-1940 (Box 3)
  - Seventy-Fifth Anniversary - Budget, 1939-1940 (Box 3)
  - Seventy-Fifth Anniversary - Alumnae House, 1939-1940 (Box 3)
  - 300,000 Gallon (gal.) Suction Tank, 1936-1937 (Box 3)
  - [Utilities] Sprinklers, 1937 (Box 3)
  - [Chapel] Chapel Gate, 1932 (Box 3)
  - [Alumnae House] Alumnae House Road, 1932 (Box 3)
  - [Central Heating Plant] Boiler Room Power Plant, Construction, 1926 (Box 3)
  - Switchboard, 1932 (Box 3)
  - [Central Heating Plant] New Boilers (3 and 4), 1933-1934 (Box 3)
  - [Utilities - Heating and Cooling] Steam Turbine and Condenser - Unit #5, 1932-1933 (Box 3)
  - [Powerhouse Theater] Power Plant - Coal Pockets, 1926-1943 (Box 4)
  - [Powerhouse Theater] Power Plant - Chimney, 1908 (Box 4)
  - [Powerhouse Theater] Power Plant - Coal Conveyor, 1927 (Box 4)
  - [Powerhouse Theater] Power Plant - GE Generating Set, Switchboard and Motors, 1908 (Box 4)
  - [Central Heating Plant] Boiler House Alterations, 1917-1927 (Box 4)
  - [Utilities - Heating and Cooling] Additions to Heating, Ventilating and Mechanical Equipment of V.C., 1916 (Box 4)
  - [Utilities - Sewer] Sewage Disposal - Plans and Correspondence, 1893-1895 (Box 4)
  - [Utilities - Sewer] Sewer, Northeast Campus, 1926-1927 (Box 4)
  - [Utilities - Sewer] Sewer to Kendrick, 1926 (Box 4)
  - [Utilities - Sewer] North Hall, Sewer Pump, 1927 (Box 4)
  - [Utilities - Sewer] Sewer on College Avenue - Contracts and Specifications, 1944 (Box 4)
  - [Utilities - Heating and Cooling] Temperature Controls Dorms and THERM - Administrative Buildings, 1983-1984 (Box 4)
  - [Utilities - Heating and Cooling] THERM - Dorm Building Controls, 1984 (Box 4)
  - [Utilities - Heating and Cooling] THERM - Paragon Clocks, 1983-1984 (Box 4)
  - [Utilities - Heating and Cooling] THERM - Order Requisitions, 1983 (Box 4)
  - [Utilities - Heating and Cooling] THERM - Sheave Reduction, 1983 (Box 4)
  - [Utilities - Heating and Cooling] Central Heating Plant and Steam Distribution System Annual Maintenance Shutdown, 1983 (Box 4)
  - [Utilities - Heating and Cooling] Hot Water Raymond and College Specifications, 1983 (Box 4)
  - [Utilities - Heating and Cooling] THERM - Clean Chimneys, 1983 (Box 4)
  - [Utilities - Heating and Cooling] THERM - Independent Hot Water, 1983-1984 (Box 4)
  - [Utilities - Heating and Cooling] THERM - Dom. Hot Water, 1983 (Box 4)
  - [Utilities - Heating and Cooling] THERM - Gas Main, 1984 (Box 4)
  - [Utilities - Heating and Cooling] Summer Shutdown Bids, 1984 (Box 4)
  - [Utilities - Heating and Cooling] THERM - Clean Boilers, 1983 (Box 4)
  - [Utilities - Heating and Cooling] THERM - M/P Valves, 1983 (Box 4)
  - [Utilities - Heating and Cooling] THERM - Pressure Regulator Valves (PRV's) and Remotes, 1983 (Box 4)
  - [Utilities - Heating and Cooling] THERM - Chiller Controls, 1983 (Box 4)
  - [Utilities - Heating and Cooling] THERM - Repair Manholes, 1983 (Box 4)
  - [Utilities - Heating and Cooling] THERM, 1983-1984 (Box 4)
  - [Utilities - Heating and Cooling] Vassar College Energy Management Program Priority "A" Projects, Agenda for Discussion, 1983 (Box 4)
  - [Utilities - Heating and Cooling] THERM Energy Resources Management Program, 1983 (Box 4)
  - [Utilities - Heating and Cooling] Energy Management Program Summary Updates Capital Spending Program, 1983 (Box 4)
  - [Utilities - Heating and Cooling] THERM Energy Resources Management, 1983 (Box 4)
  - [Utilities - Heating and Cooling] Energy Management, 1982-1983 (Box 4)
  - [Utilities - Heating and Cooling] THERM - Proposed Projects, 1983 (Box 4)
  - [Utilities - Heating and Cooling] THERM - OTW "A" Priority Estimates Costs, 1983-1984 (Box 4)
  - Technical Resource Management Co., 1983 (Box 4)
  - Saren Engineering Inc. General, 1983-1984 (Box 4)
  - [Utilities] Manhole Reports, 1983 Aug (Box 4)
  - [Skinner Hall] Acoustical Survey (Mr. Semmens), Sound Studio - Skinner Physics Lecture Hall, 1953 (Box 4)
  - Academic Equipment - Microscopes, 1955-1971 (Box 4)
  - Civil Defense - Minutes, 1962 (Box 4)
  - Academic Equipment and Furniture, 1954-1973 (Box 4)
  - Academic Equipment and Furniture - Extinguishers, 1967-1971 (Box 4)
  - Architects - Mr. Ralph L. Gionta, 1965 (Box 4)
  - Civil Defence - V. C., 1951-1971 (Box 5)
  - College Research Center, 1965-1968 (Box 5)
  - Monthly Cost Reports - Food Service, 1969-1970 (Box 5)
  - Ford Foundation, 1963-1964 (Box 5)
  - Governance, 1961-1966 (Box 5)
  - Mellon Program, 1950-1968 (Box 5)
  - Hudson - Champlain Celebration, 1958-1959 (Box 5)
  - Mid - Hudson Association of Colleges, 1962-1969 (Box 5)
  - Middle States Evaluation Vassar College, 1957-1958 (Box 5)
  - Committee on Business Administration, 1953-1962 (Box 5)
  - Executive Committee, 1956-1968 (Box 5)
  - Committee on Construction Financing, 1964-1966 (Box 5)
  - Committee on Space Allocation, 1966-1969 (Box 5)
  - Committee on Undergraduate Life, 1963 (Box 5)
  - Proposed Summer Use of the Campus General Correspondence, 1959-1969; (2 folders) (Box 5)
  - Summer Educational Program for the Disadvantaged, 1969 (Box 5)
  - Minnewaska Conference, 1968 (Box 5)
  - Summer Institute in Geology, 1966-1969 (Box 5)
  - State Education Dept. Conference on College Building, 1965 (Box 5)
  - State Education Department Summer, 1965 (Box 5)
  - Summer Institute in Earth Sciences, 1960-1965; (2 folders) (Box 5)
  - Summer Institute in English, 1964-1965 (Box 5)
  - Summer Workshop in Russian, 1963; (3 folders) (Box 5)
  - International Nursery School Conference, 1962-1963 (Box 5)
  - Russian Language Institute, 1961 (Box 5)
  - Annual Meeting of the Association of Colleges and Universities of the State of New York, 1961; (3 folders) (Box 5)
  - Summer Language School, 1960-1961; (2 folders) (Box 5)
  - Institute in Community Leadership, 1960-1961 (Box 5)
  - Science and Engineering Institute, 1969-1971 (Box 5)
  - Summer Workshop in American History, 1960 (Box 5)
  - Talladega Alumni Association, 1960-1969 (Box 5)
  - Summer Institute, 1954-1958 (Box 5)
  - [Olmsted Hall] Division 2 - Site Work, Biological Sciences Building Vassar College, undated (Box 5)
  - [Olmsted Hall] Biological Sciences Building Mechanical Specification, No Addenda’s, undated (Box 5)
  - [Chicago Hall] Language Building - Progress Photos, 1958 (Box 5)
  - [Chapel] Roof Repairs, 1950-1952 (Box 5)
  - [College Center] College Center Renovation, 1973-1976 (Box 6)
  - [Chapel] Roof Repairs and Rehabilitation, 1953-1954 (Box 6)
  - [Avery Hall] Avery Alterations, 1918 (Box 6)
  - [Baldwin Hall] Baldwin House, 1939-1940 (Box 6)
  - [Swift Hall] Infirmary E. V. Anderson [Change Orders, Payments, Etc.], 1939-1940; (3 folders) (Box 6)
  - [Swift Hall] Infirmary Budget, 1940 (Box 6)
  - [Swift Hall] Infirmary President, 1939-1940 (Box 6)
  - [Swift Hall] Infirmary Equipment - Medical, 1939-1940 (Box 6)
  - [Swift Hall] Infirmary Equipment - Other, 1939-1940 (Box 6)
  - [Swift Hall] Infirmary Estimates, 1939 (Box 6)
  - [Swift Hall] Infirmary Faulkner, 1938-1940 (Box 6)
  - [Swift Hall] Infirmary Garage, 1939-1940 (Box 6)
  - [Swift Hall] Infirmary General, 1938-1940 (Box 6)
  - [Swift Hall] Infirmary - Lightning Protection, 1940 (Box 6)
  - [Swift Hall] Infirmary Trustees, 1938-1940 (Box 6)
  - [Swift Hall] Infirmary X-ray, 1939-1940 (Box 6)
  - [Swift Hall] [X-ray G. E.], 1939 (Box 6)
  - [Swift Hall] Infirmary Faulkner, 1939 (Box 6)
  - [Blodgett Hall] Blodgett - Original Specs, 1926 (Box 6)
  - [Blodgett Hall] Blodgett Hall Furnishings, 1928-1931 (Box 6)
  - [Blodgett Hall] Costs, 1927-1928 (Box 6)
  - [Blodgett Hall] Blodgett, Mrs. John W., 1925-1931 (Box 6)
  - [Blodgett Hall] General Blodgett Hall, 1925-1931 (Box 6)
  - [Blodgett Hall] Blodgett Euthenics, 1926-1941 (Box 6)
  - [Blodgett Hall] Blodgett Hall Alterations, 1955-1956 (Box 6)
  - [Blodgett Hall] York and Sawyer Orders and General Correspondence, 1925-1931; (2 folders) (Box 6)
  - [Blodgett Hall] MacCracken, President - Correspondence Regarding Blodgett Hall, 1925-1928 (Box 6)
  - [Blodgett Hall] Furnishings of Blodgett Hall, Euthenics, 1928 (Box 6)
  - [Blodgett Hall] Equipment, 1926-1928 (Box 6)
  - [Chapel] Specification for Alterations to Vassar College Chapel, undated (Box 6)
  - [Chapel] Chapel Acoustics Renovation, 1925 (Box 6)
  - [Chapel] Chapel Alterations, 1931 (Box 6)
  - [Chapel] Public Address System, 1937-1938 (Box 6)
  - [Chapel] Chapel Organ, 1934-1939 (Box 6)
  - [Chapel] Chapel Heating and Ventilating System, 1902 (Box 6)
  - [Chapel] Chapel (Proposed - Small) (Not Built), 1952-1953 (Box 6)
  - [Chicago Hall] Language Building - Contract Award, 1958 (Box 6)
  - [Cushing House] Cushing Hall, 1926-1927; (2 folders) (Box 6)
  - Anderson, Edgar V., 1926-1928 (Box 6)
  - Allen, Mrs. Arthur M., 1926-1927 (Box 7)
  - Cinders, 1927 (Box 7)
  - Costs, 1926-1929 (Box 7)
  - Equipment, 1926-1927 (Box 7)
  - Allen and Collens, 1926-1929 (Box 7)
  - [Davison House] Specifications for Alterations and Additions to Davison Hall Dormitory, 1926 (Box 7)
  - [Faculty Housing] 164 College Avenue - Dean's House, 1931 (Box 7)
  - Vassar College Greenhouse, 1940 (Box 7)
  - [Cushing House] Cushing Hall Furnishings, 1927-1930 (Box 7)
  - General, 1926-1928 (Box 7)
  - Place, Clyde R., 1926 (Box 7)
  - Service Building, 1925 (Box 7)
  - [Skinner Hall] Skinner Hall, 1930-1938 (Box 7)
  - [Strong House] Strong Hall Heating System, 1927; (3 folders) (Box 7)
  - [Skinner Hall] Skinner Hall, Charles Collens Correspondence, 1929-1932 (Box 7)
  - [Skinner Hall] Heating, Electric and Plumbing, 1930 (Box 7)
  - [Skinner Hall] Anderson, Edgar V., 1930 (Box 7)
  - [Skinner Hall] Bids Skinner Hall, 1929-1930; (2 folders) (Box 7)
  - [Skinner Hall] Skinner Hall Construction - Photographs, 1930 (Box 7)
  - [Skinner Hall] Skinner Hall Finishing Work and Contract Payments, 1930-1931 (Box 7)
  - [Skinner Hall] General Contract and Specifications, 1930 (Box 7)
  - [Skinner Hall] Skinner Hall Budget Statement and Items not Included in General Contract, 1930-1931 (Box 7)
  - [Skinner Hall] Frank and DuBois - Insurance Skinner Hall, 1929-1931 (Box 7)
  - [Skinner Hall] Skinner Hall Electrical Fixtures and Furnishings, 1930-1931 (Box 7)
  - [Skinner Hall] Clyde R. Place Correspondence, Skinner Hall, 1930-1931 (Box 7)
  - [Skinner Hall] Sound Studio - Skinner Hall (Installation by Morton Lee), 1948-1954 (Box 7)
  - [Faculty Housing] Head Warden's House (Pratt House), 1915 (Box 7)
  - [Vassar Brothers Laboratory Contract and Bond], 1938 (Box 7)
  - [Vassar Brothers Laboratory Torn Down], 1938 (Box 7)
  - [Faculty Housing] Outline Specifications For House #4 for Milton Wend, 1926 (Box 8)
  - [Faculty Housing] Ellis House - Wing Farm House, 1940 (Box 8)
  - [Faculty Housing] Griffin House Specifications, 1939 (Box 8)
  - [Faculty Housing] Hopper House Specifications, 1939 (Box 8)
  - [Faculty Housing] Howson House Specifications, 1939 (Box 8)
  - [Faculty Housing] Myers House - Specifications, 1936 (Box 8)
  - [Faculty Housing] Piccirilli house, 1939 (Box 8)
  - [Faculty Housing] Terry Cottage Rock Wool Insulation, 1938 (Box 8)
  - [Faculty Housing] Elsworth House Specifications, undated (Box 8)
  - Vassar Brothers Laboratory, 1879 (Box 8)
  - Zehe, Paul E. (Estate of), 1946 (Box 8)
  - Vassar Brothers' Institute, 1949-1950 (Box 8)
  - Sunk Mine Farm Estate of Mrs. William S. Ladd near Philipstown, New York, 1951-1952 (Box 8)
  - Market Street #112 - Wylie Property, 1940-1944 (Box 8)
  - 115 Academy Street Sale and Renovation, 1935-1940 (Box 8)
  - Property - Vassar College, 1944-1945 (Box 8)
  - [Faculty Housing] Property 145 College Avenue, 1948 (Box 8)
  - Lisburne Grange Maps, undated (Box 8)